Jonathan Downing

5098 Demorest Dr Grove City, OH 43212 765.215.5723 | <u>jtdowning@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedIn</u> | <u>Git hub</u>

SUMMARY

Passion of learning software development, web design, user experience, and automation testing. Majority of my career lead, train, develop, and manage call center employees. Took on multiple software implementations projects and found an appreciation for software development, technology, and quality assurance.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Object Oriented Programming:** classes and objects, interfaces, access modifiers, packages, the Java classpath, class modeling, encapsulation, inheritance, and polymorphism, UML class diagrams
- Web Application Development: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Servlets, JSP, Spring Web MVC, Tomcat
- Database Programming: JDBC, table design and creation, SQL queries and DML, PostgreSQL, E/R diagrams
- **Development tools and techniques:** Agile, unit testing (JUnit), integration testing, TDD, unix command line navigation, Git, Eclipse, Selenium, Cucumber

EDUCATION

Tech Elevator December 2017

• 14-week Java coding boot camp learning how to develop dynamic web based software systems using the Java programming language and platform.

Ball State University

May 2006

Bachelor of Science- Information Systems and Operations Management; Business minor

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

- www.seanstrahan.com
- mini-capstone 1 Vending Machine
- mini-capstone 2 National Park reservation

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Ohio Attorney General, Claims Account Representative

July 2015 – August 2017

- Representative on the Non-Tax matters placed outbound calls to taxpayers work out payment arrangements; take inbound calls from taxpayers constructing payment plans, disputes, and tax offsets
- Assigned to the Special Counsel unit, acted as a liaison between taxpayer and outside vendors and attorneys;
 assisted on getting information from different departments throughout vary state agencies

iQor, Supervisor October 2013- July 2015

- Increased site production by 210% after taking over team in October 2013
- Trained employees on quality standards, customer service, and increase in production
- Educated employees on FDCPA, TCPA, and CFPB
- Developed production strategies for two other call centers; responsible for over 100 representatives on training

West Asset Management, Supervisor

February 2012 - February 2013

- Achieved our overall team and department goals; increased client rankings
- Analyzed data, implemented new dialing techniques, and put together strategic planning for maximum profitability

Allstate Insurance, Bodily Claim Adjuster

April 2011 – February 2012

- Communicated with customers and third parties regarding their accident
- Determined liability and work with other carriers to make sure payments and necessary repairs were made on time

Premiere Credit of North America, Collections Manager

March 2010 – April 2011

- Introduced as administrative wage garnishment unit manager
- Implemented new dialer system, worked with software developers and managment
- Developed and trained new employees into post default collections

Sallie Mae, Collections Manager

September 2006 – March 2010

- Developed and improved quality assurance standards
- Implemented dialer systems, working with software developers and system administrators
- Increased cash flow in operations by 120% in four month period
- Analyzed and developed strategic dialing schedules for team and department
- Awarded top supervisor in Private Collections nine different times in a 12 month period